The world is changed.
O mundo mudou.
I feel it in the water.
Eu sinto na agua.
I feel it in the earth.
Eu sinto na terra.
I smell it in the air.
Eu sinto no ar.
Much that once was is lost, for none now live who remember it.
Muito do que existia se perdeu, pois ninguem vive que se lembre.
It began with the forging of the Great Rings.
Comecou com a forja dos Grandes Aneis.
Three were given to the Elves, immortal, wisest and fairest of all beings.
Tres foram dados aos Elfos, imortais, os mais sabios e belos de todos os seres.
Seven to the Dwarf-Lords, great miners and craftsmen of the mountain halls.
Sete para os Senhores dos Anoes, grandes mineradores e artesaos dos saloes da montanha.
And nine, nine rings were gifted to the race of Men, who above all else desire power.
E nove, nove aneis foram dados a raca dos Homens, que acima de tudo desejam o poder.
For within these rings was bound the strength and the will to govern each race.
Pois dentro destes aneis estava a forca e a vontade de governar cada raca.
But they were all of them deceived, for another ring was made.
Mas todos eles foram enganados, pois outro anel foi feito.
In the land of Mordor, in the fires of Mount Doom, the Dark Lord Sauron forged a master ring.
Na terra de Mordor, nas chamas da Montanha da Perdicao, o Senhor das Trevas Sauron forjou um anel mestre.
And into this ring he poured his cruelty, his malice and his will to dominate all life.
E neste anel ele despejou sua crueldade, sua malicia e sua vontade de dominar toda a vida.
One ring to rule them all.
Um anel para governar todos eles.